This is the car that broke down last time, right?
이거 지난번에 고장난 그 차 맞죠?
It's been repaired
수리됐어요
yes
예
Oh, that's great. I'm so lucky.
아, 그거 참 좋네요. 정말 행운이에요.
I see you guys are going out, so be careful on the road.
너희들이 나가는 것 같으니 길 조심해라.
Then let's do this first
그럼 먼저 이것부터 하자
us
우리를
How bad is the current situation?
현재 상황은 얼마나 나쁜가요?
Well, this is also the first time I've encountered this.
글쎄요, 저도 이런 일을 처음 접했습니다.
Shouldn't I be trapped here forever?
영원히 여기에 갇혀 있으면 안되는 걸까?
Can't we go back?
돌아갈 수는 없을까?
No way
안 돼요
Don't worry, just fix it. It can be fixed.
걱정하지 마시고 고치시면 됩니다.
Just fix it. Just fix it.
그냥 고치세요 그냥 고치세요
It'll be fine if it's fixed. It can be fixed.
고치면 괜찮을텐데 고칠 수 있어요.
Let's go home first
먼저 집에 가자
this time before
이번에는 전에
I don't think there's any need to ask anything in particular.
특별히 물어볼 필요는 없을 것 같아요.
Because the existence of a time machine is ridiculous in the first place.
애초에 타임머신의 존재 자체가 말도 안 되는 일이니까요.
no matter who made it
누가 만들었든 상관없어
Or even from the magic lamp
아니면 마법의 램프에서도
I don't think it's a big deal
큰 문제는 아닌 것 같아요
This shouldn't be made by you, right?
이건 당신이 만들어서는 안 되는 일이겠죠?
So where did this one come from?
그럼 이건 어디서 나온 걸까요?
I picked it up
나는 그것을 집어 들었다
Turns out I picked it up
그러고 보니 내가 집어들었다
You actually
당신은 실제로
I actually picked up a time machine
사실 타임머신을 타고 왔어
The time machine turned out to be picked up
타임머신이 픽업되는 것으로 밝혀졌습니다.
He actually said he picked up a time machine
실제로 그는 타임머신을 집어 들었다고 말했다
Jiongwan
지온관
Please don't mention my husband's name easily
남편 이름 함부로 언급하지 마세요
There is no need for us to meet with the chairman in the future.
앞으로는 회장님을 만날 필요가 없습니다.
please leave
떠나주세요
I told you to go quickly
빨리 가라고 했잖아
sorry
죄송합니다
I'm really sorry for you
정말 미안해요
It is my fault
이건 내 잘못이야
It's me who didn't teach my son well
내 아들을 잘 가르치지 못한 건 나야
will harm you
당신에게 해를 끼칠 것입니다
Lost a precious child just like that
그렇게 소중한 아이를 잃었어
I also know no matter what
나도 무슨 일이 있어도 알아
I can't even get your forgiveness
난 너의 용서조차 받을 수 없어
I can't give you any comfort
나는 당신에게 어떤 위로도 줄 수 없습니다
I will hold the mood of atonement
속죄의 기분을 품겠습니다
Spend the rest of your life
남은 인생을 보내세요
I will definitely let myself
나는 확실히 나 자신을 허락할 것이다
Tortured every minute
매분마다 고문당함
sorry
죄송합니다
can you really do it
정말 할 수 있어?
You really have a way
당신에겐 정말 방법이 있어요
Will you live a life of torture?
고문의 삶을 살 것인가?
i will do that
나는 그렇게 할 것이다
I will let myself live like that
나도 그렇게 살도록 놔둘게
I'm really sorry for you
정말 미안해요
That bastard thing
그 놈의 것
I hope they are a family
나는 그들이 가족이기를 바란다.
Can live in dire straits for the rest of his life
남은 생애 동안 극심한 곤경에 처할 수 있습니다
No matter how incompetent your child is,
아이가 아무리 무능해도
But I have to uncover the child’s scars with my own hands
하지만 내 손으로 아이의 상처를 벗겨내야만 해
How difficult is it
얼마나 어렵나요?
I know it too
나도 알아
I'm grateful to you for that.
그것에 대해 감사드립니다.
even so
비록 그렇다 하더라도
Fortunately, I have a place to come back to.
다행히 돌아갈 곳이 있다.
How about we just get drunk today?
오늘은 그냥 취하는 게 어때?
Anyway, there’s nothing left to do tonight
어쨌든 오늘 밤에는 할 일이 하나도 없네
- Eat more - Okay
- 더 먹어 - 알았어
I thought it was all fixed
다 해결된 ​​줄 알았는데
It turned out not to be the case
그렇지 않은 것으로 밝혀졌습니다
It's not all bad
다 나쁜 건 아니야
Anyway, once I go back
어쨌든 일단 돌아가면
Have to go to work soon
빨리 출근해야 해
At least if you continue to stay here
적어도 계속 여기에 머물면
You don’t have to suffer that 6:30 in the morning
아침 6시 30분까지 고생할 필요는 없어
35 minutes 40 minutes
35분 40분
The alarm that rings every 5 minutes is disturbing.
5분마다 울리는 알람소리가 짜증스럽네요.
Not bad
나쁘지 않다
I can also see my mother in her youth a few more times
나는 또한 어머니의 젊은 시절을 몇 번 더 볼 수 있습니다
Take more breaths of fresh air
신선한 공기를 더 많이 마시세요
Hagfish even sells for only 2,000 won
먹장어는 2000원에도 팔아요
You can’t even come up with 2,000 won
2000원도 안 되잖아
Are you trying to draw a clear line with me now?
지금 나와 명확한 선을 긋으려는 건가요?
Aren't you still here?
아직 여기 없나요?
In fact, the money I prepared is almost gone.
사실 준비한 돈이 거의 없어졌어요.
Because I didn't plan to stay so long
왜냐면 난 그렇게 오래 머물 생각은 없었거든
I didn't expect to be trapped here either.
나도 여기에 갇힐 줄은 몰랐다.
Mark Six Lottery
마크 식스 복권
Don’t you have the winning numbers memorized?
당첨번호는 외우지 않으셨나요?
What do you think
어떻게 생각하나요
hateful
증오스러운
What a useless conscience
얼마나 쓸모없는 양심인가
It doesn't matter
그것은 중요하지 않습니다
Anyway, we are all able-bodied
어쨌든 우리는 모두 건장한 사람들이다.
We even know the future direction
우리는 미래의 방향조차 알고 있다
You can definitely make a lot of money if you make up your mind.
마음만 먹으면 분명 돈을 많이 벌 수 있을 거예요.
Are you still afraid of starving to death?
아직도 굶어죽는 것이 두려우신가요?
but
하지만
How could the time machine be picked up?
타임머신은 어떻게 태울 수 있었나요?
Even walking on the roadside
길가를 걷는 것조차
It’s hard to find 500 won coins
500원짜리 동전 찾기가 힘들어요
I'm also very curious about this matter
나도 이 문제가 너무 궁금하다
Then how did you pick it up?
그럼 어떻게 집어 들었나요?
It was a day of pouring rain
비가 추적추적 내리는 날이었는데
You've gone off course
넌 진로를 벗어났어
Searching again
다시 검색 중
Not only did the navigation fail that day,
그날 내비게이션이 실패했을 뿐만 아니라,
My vision was blurry because of the rain.
비 때문에 시야가 흐려졌다.
I was on the road where I didn't even know where I was.
나는 내가 어디에 있는지조차 모르는 길에 있었다.
Been driving for a while
한동안 운전을 했어
Then we met
그러다가 우리는 만났어요
Just in front of the old bridge
오래된 다리 바로 앞
Is it like being thrown in there?
거기에 던져진 것 같나요?
The car door is still open
차 문은 아직 열려있습니다
There was even a sign in the car that said
차 안에는 다음과 같은 표지판도 있었습니다.
Tell me to drive across the old bridge ahead or something like that
앞에 오래된 다리를 건너 운전하라고 말해주세요.
and instructions for use
및 사용 지침
I want you to drive past the one in front of you
네 앞에 있는 차를 지나쳐갔으면 좋겠어
It's like I'm waiting to be discovered
마치 내가 발견되기를 기다리고 있는 것 같아요
Now that I think about it, that's not the only thing that's strange.
지금 생각해보면 이상한 점은 그것뿐만이 아니다.
The day I bumped into you
너와 마주친 날
Do you remember what you asked me?
나한테 물어본 거 기억나?
That question about the phone
전화에 관한 그 질문
This is not a car that can hit just about anywhere.
이것은 아무데나 칠 수 있는 차가 아닙니다.
Did you call anyone?
누구한테 전화했어?
You must have been beaten
당신은 틀림없이 구타를 당했을 것입니다.
Usually inattentive while driving
운전할 때 보통 부주의함
Isn't it more likely to cause an accident?
사고가 날 확률이 더 높지 않나요?
What's strange
뭐가 이상한데?
Actually that day
사실 그날
Someone really called me
누군가가 정말로 나에게 전화를 했어요.
yes
예
What did you say
뭐라고 하셨나요
Only you can solve this matter from beginning to end
오직 당신만이 이 문제를 처음부터 끝까지 해결할 수 있습니다
But I had no idea at the time
하지만 그 당시에는 전혀 몰랐습니다
I just dismissed it as a strange call and ignored it.
그냥 이상한 전화라고 무시하고 무시했어요.
But no matter how I thought about it later, I felt that
그런데 나중에 아무리 생각해도 그런 느낌이 들었어요.
That's not what someone who knows nothing would say.
아무것도 모르는 사람이 할 말은 아니다.
Who could that person be?
그 사람은 누구일까요?
I don't know either
나도 모르겠어요
Are you OK
괜찮으세요
The pace of walking is a bit strange
걷는 속도가 좀 이상해요
I'm fine
잘 지내요
You can’t apply for insurance claims here anyway.
어쨌든 여기서는 보험 청구를 신청할 수 없습니다.
It seems this is not the first time I have heard this sentence
이 문장을 처음 듣는 것은 아닌 것 같습니다.
I'm fine
잘 지내요
If I die here
내가 여기서 죽으면
Things will become quite difficult to understand
상황이 상당히 이해하기 어려워질 것입니다
I felt really confused at that time.
그땐 정말 혼란스러웠어요.
But to be honest, I'm not that confused now.
하지만 솔직히 말해서 지금은 그렇게 혼란스럽지 않습니다.
Because there is someone I want to be with
같이 있고 싶은 사람이 있으니까
if
만약에
If it's true
그것이 사실이라면
Never find a way back
절대 돌아갈 길을 찾지 마세요
I have to be trapped here for the rest of my life.
난 평생 여기서 갇혀 지내야 해요.
I seem to be able to accept it, too.
나도 받아들일 수 있을 것 같다.
If you were with me
당신이 나와 함께 있었다면
Really
정말
how about you
당신은 어떤가요
me
나
It’s useless to say more
더 말해도 소용없어
Of course not
당연히 아니지
It seems that your words and deeds are a little different from yesterday.
어제와는 말과 행동이 조금 다른 것 같습니다.
what do you mean
무슨 뜻이에요
Didn't you say you don't care?
신경 안 쓴다고 하지 않았나요?
Didn't you say that if I were here?
내가 여기 있었다면 그렇게 말하지 않았나요?
Are you willing to stay here all your life?
평생 여기에 머물 의향이 있습니까?
I thought the back of my head
뒤통수도 생각났어
A hole is almost being seen through
구멍이 거의 보일 정도다
How many hours do you plan to stay here and watch?
여기에 몇 시간이나 머물면서 볼 생각인가요?
no
아니요
I'm just curious if things are going well
일이 잘 진행되고 있는지 궁금해요
A person who is simply curious
단순히 궁금해하는 사람
Will you sigh when you see me tilting my head?
고개를 갸우뚱하는 나를 보면 한숨을 쉬겠는가?
It seems that I am the only one who is sincere.
진심인 사람은 나뿐인 것 같다.
Of course I really mean it too.
물론 나도 진심이다.
But now that it’s like this
그런데 지금은 이렇게 되니까
It would be better to meet in 2021
2021년에 만나면 더 좋을 것 같아요
Can we still rely on modern civilization
우리는 여전히 현대 문명에 의지할 수 있는가
Sorry, I won't watch it anymore
죄송합니다. 더 이상 시청하지 않겠습니다.
But can you leave the door a crack?
하지만 문에 균열을 남겨둘 수 있나요?
knew
알고 있었다
I know, I'm leaving now
알아요, 나 지금 떠날 거예요
I'm going in
나는 들어갈거야
This book has been selling very well recently
이 책은 최근에 아주 잘 팔리고 있어요
- Really? - Yeah
- 정말? - 응
- It must be interesting. - That's right.
- 재미있겠군요 - 그렇군요.
- Do you want to buy a copy and take it back? - Okay
- 한 권 사서 다시 가져갈래요? - 좋아요
Oh, thank you. Welcome back.
아, 고마워요. 다시 오신 것을 환영합니다.
- Thank you, you're welcome
- 고마워 천만에
I've already seen it
나는 이미 그것을 보았다
I think it looks good
내 생각엔 좋은 것 같아
Your writing is not bad
당신의 글은 나쁘지 않습니다
Please sign your name on the cover for me later
나중에 나를 위해 표지에 당신의 이름을 서명해 주세요
Are you feeling better?
기분이 나아졌나요?
It's okay now that I'm here
이제 괜찮아 괜찮아
That lunatic should have been caught sooner
그 미친놈은 빨리 잡았어야 했는데
but
하지만
Why don't you come to school since you've been discharged from the hospital?
병원에서 퇴원한 이후로 학교에 오지 않겠습니까?
Is it because of our relationship?
우리 관계 때문일까?
it's not like that
그건 그렇지 않아
Then it's time to go to school
그럼 학교에 갈 시간이야
Come back soon
곧 돌아와
Teachers and classmates are waiting for you
선생님과 반 친구들이 당신을 기다리고 있습니다
Thanks
감사해요
See you at school then
그럼 학교에서 보자
Meet Lee Soon Ae at school
이순애를 학교에서 만나다
In the past, I only heard them asking me to meet at school.
예전에는 학교에서 만나자고 하는 말만 들었어요.
I feel so scared
너무 무서워요
It seems like it really doesn't matter now
이제 정말 별거 아닌 것 같지만
that's great
그거 정말 대단해
correct
옳은
I've prepared a gift for you
당신을 위한 선물을 준비했어요
Is it the official printed version?
정식인쇄본인가요?
"Lee Soon Ae"
"이순애"
The name is also printed clearly
이름도 선명하게 인쇄되어 있어요
sign your name for me
나를 위해 당신의 이름을 서명해 주세요
Signed long ago
오래 전에 서명함
Open the first page and take a look
첫 페이지를 열어서 살펴보세요.
"To my best friend"
"내 가장 친한 친구에게"
"Only my Y Yunying"
"오직 내 Y윤잉"
Thank you
감사합니다
Really thank you very much
정말 고마워요
This is the greatest gift in my life
이건 내 인생의 가장 큰 선물이야
Do you really know something before you fix it?
고치기 전에 정말 알고 있는 게 있나요?
If that were the case, I would have fixed it long ago.
그랬다면 오래 전에 고쳤을 겁니다.
How does that go
어떻게 되나요?
The rest of the procedure should go smoothly.
나머지 절차는 원활하게 진행되어야 합니다.
The chairman seems to have given an explanation
회장님께서 설명을 하신 것 같습니다.
Make him admit everything and pay the price
모든 것을 인정하고 대가를 치르게 하라
It seems that's what he told your dad.
그 사람이 네 아버지한테 그렇게 말한 것 같더라.
The chairman is having a hard time now
회장님 지금 힘들어요
What else is needed at this time?
이때 또 무엇이 필요합니까?
What we need most is family.
우리에게 가장 필요한 것은 가족입니다.
But from now on he will be left alone
하지만 이제부터 그 사람은 혼자 남게 될 거야
Why do you open the door so wide?
왜 이렇게 문을 활짝 열어요?
Haijun
하이준
Haven't you seen what people outside are doing?
밖에 사람들이 무엇을 하고 있는지 못 보셨나요?
What should you do if someone comes in and hurts you? It's too dangerous.
누군가 들어와서 다치게 하면 어떻게 해야 할까요?너무 위험합니다.
Who else in this village can be better than my son?
이 마을에서 내 아들보다 나은 사람이 또 누가 있겠는가?
More dangerous
더 위험한
I thought you had gone back
난 당신이 돌아간 줄 알았는데
Thought you had enough of yours
넌 네 것만으로도 충분하다고 생각했어
The so-called family members who do all kinds of evil
온갖 악행을 저지르는 이른바 가족들
Just leave without saying goodbye
작별인사도 없이 그냥 떠나가
I would have done this if I could
할 수만 있다면 이렇게 했을 텐데
thank you for not doing that
그러지 않아서 고마워요
I always hope to see you one last time
항상 마지막으로 만나길 바라요
Don't you hate me?
당신은 나를 싫어하지 않습니까?
Because of me, you are going through things that you don’t have to go through.
나 때문에 너는 겪지 않아도 될 일들을 겪고 있는 거다.
Don't even know how long this will last
이게 언제까지 지속될지조차 모르겠어
Just because I'm worried that you might think this way
그냥 니가 그렇게 생각할까봐 걱정되니까
So I want to meet you again
그래서 또 만나고 싶어
Want to tell you I'm okay
난 괜찮다고 말하고 싶어
On the contrary, thank you very much
오히려 정말 감사해요.
I really want to tell you this
나는 이것을 꼭 당신에게 말하고 싶습니다.
Thanks to you
고마워
Now I can at least make things right
이제 난 적어도 일을 바로잡을 수 있어
Really sorry
정말 미안해요
Let you see my shameful appearance
부끄러운 내 모습을 보여주세요
I'm still thinking
아직도 생각 중이야
How long do I need to wait before I can tell you this?
이 말을 하려면 얼마나 기다려야 합니까?
Fortunately I could tell you 30 years in advance
다행히도 30년 전에 미리 말씀드릴 수 있었습니다
What a blessing
얼마나 큰 축복인가
where did you go
어디 갔어?
Went to meet someone
누군가를 만나러 갔다
Why are you so listless?
왜 이렇게 무기력해?
us
우리를
Can be done in the blink of an eye
눈 깜짝할 사이에 할 수 있는 일
span 30 years
30년에 걸쳐
But it made me realize
하지만 그게 나에게 깨닫게 해줬어
Some people have to endure it
어떤 사람들은 그걸 견뎌야 해
every day for these 30 years
지난 30년 동안 매일
Did you go to see your grandpa?
할아버지를 만나러 갔나요?
I'm not regretting what we did
난 우리가 한 일을 후회하지 않아요
I know and understand
나는 알고 이해한다
Maybe this will be our chance
어쩌면 이번이 우리에게 기회가 될지도 몰라
Although we can't go back right now
비록 지금은 돌아갈 수 없지만
But that means more time here
하지만 그건 여기서 더 많은 시간을 보낸다는 뜻이야
How about spending time like we didn't have before.
이전에 없었던 시간을 보내는 것은 어떨까요?
"A time we didn't have before"
"이전에는 없었던 시간"
In other words, the time that I wanted to have but couldn’t.
즉, 갖고 싶었지만 가질 수 없었던 시간.
Because I saw them again 30 years later
30년 뒤에 다시 봤으니까
So create a beautiful memory for them
그러니 그들에게 아름다운 추억을 만들어주세요
It should be fine
괜찮을 거야
do you like fishing
당신은 낚시를 좋아합니까
i know a good place
나 좋은 곳 알아
But I don’t want to go alone
하지만 혼자 가고 싶지 않아요
Do you know what my original dream was?
내 원래 꿈이 뭔지 알아?
Live an ordinary life and have an ordinary job
평범한 삶을 살고 평범한 직업을 가지세요
alone after retirement
퇴직 후 혼자
Just spend your whole life fishing leisurely like this
그냥 평생 이렇게 여유롭게 낚시를 해보세요
Are you alone
당신은 혼자입니까?
Don’t you have family or children?
가족이나 자녀가 없나요?
may be
아마도
Too
도
For you
당신을 위한
My family is not impressed
우리 가족은 감동받지 않아요
But something seems to have changed now
그런데 지금은 뭔가 달라진 것 같아요
I hope someone can stay with me
누군가가 나와 함께 머물 수 있기를 바랍니다
We can talk and laugh together
함께 이야기하고 웃을 수 있어요
You can also ask for help
도움을 요청할 수도 있습니다.
I also want to live that kind of life
나도 그런 삶을 살고 싶다
Of course life is like that
물론 인생도 그렇죠
You can definitely have that life
분명 그런 삶을 살 수 있을 거야
can i really do that
내가 정말 그렇게 할 수 있을까?
of course
물론
If you decide you want to live that life
그런 삶을 살고 싶다고 결심했다면
I will do my best to help you
나는 당신을 돕기 위해 최선을 다할 것입니다
Then I beg you
그럼 부탁할게
"Plea"
"항변"
Reduce your alcohol intake as soon as possible
알코올 섭취를 가능한 한 빨리 줄이세요.
If you don’t want to take those nasty medicines all the time
이렇게 안좋은 약을 계속 먹고 싶지 않다면
Remember to eat on time
시간에 맞춰 식사하는 것을 잊지 마세요
Start regular health check-ups after 8 years
8년 만에 정기 건강검진 시작
OK
좋아요
Just no more worries
더 이상 걱정하지 마세요.
Only then can I live a life of talking and laughing
그래야만 말하고 웃는 삶을 살 수 있다
Apart from these things that are good to me
이 외에도 나에게 좋은 것들은
Didn't you ask me to do it for you?
나한테 해달라고 하지 않았어?
Just take me fishing occasionally
가끔씩 낚시를 데려가 주세요
The first time I went fishing was with my seniors after I joined the company
입사 후 처음으로 낚시를 갔던 것은 선배님들과 함께였습니다.
Found it suits me very well
나한테 너무 잘 어울리는 것 같아
At that time, I thought it would be great to know earlier.
그때는 일찍 알았으면 좋겠다고 생각했어요.
If you feel good today
오늘 기분이 좋으면
You can bring me here early
일찍 여기로 데려와도 돼
The real fun is night fishing
진짜 재미는 밤낚시
You can also cook ramen and eat it
라면을 끓여서 먹을 수도 있어요
alright
괜찮은
- Here you go - Thank you
- 여기요 - 감사합니다
Blow it
날려 버려라
That's good
좋아요
But is this enough?
하지만 이것으로 충분합니까?
that's enough for me
난 그거면 충분해
Oh my god float
맙소사 플로트
Grandpa, I told you to wait a while
할아버지, 제가 좀 기다리라고 했어요
But the float has moved
그런데 플로트가 움직였어.
Didn't move at all
전혀 움직이지 않았어
The beauty of fishing is to be patient and let it go
낚시의 묘미는 인내심을 갖고 놔두는 것
Okay, we'll come back when we get there.
좋아요, 거기 도착하면 다시 오겠습니다.
The last person to arrive wants to buy spicy rice cakes
마지막에 도착한 사람은 매운떡을 사고 싶어한다
Then let's go
그럼 가자
Even the foul is so cute
반칙마저도 너무 귀여워
What are you doing
뭐하세요
I won't
나는하지 않을 것이다
What should I say louder?
무슨 말을 더 크게 해야 할까?
I can't ride a bicycle
나는 자전거를 탈 수 없다
You two go ahead and leave me alone.
너희 둘은 나를 내버려두고 가세요.
How can I not ride a bicycle at this age?
이 나이에 어떻게 자전거를 탈 수 없나요?
Why didn't your father even teach you this?
네 아버지는 왜 이런 것도 가르쳐 주지 않았니?
He can't ride either
그 사람도 못 타요
His legs are a bit inconvenient
다리가 좀 불편해요
Yeah
응
if
만약에
If he's okay
만약 그 사람이 괜찮다면
Do you want to teach me this too?
나한테도 이런 걸 가르쳐 줄래?
As a father, who doesn’t want to teach his children to ride a bicycle?
아버지로서 자녀에게 자전거 타는 법을 가르치고 싶지 않은 사람이 어디 있겠습니까?
Whenever I see
볼때마다
He must be very sad that someone else is teaching their children.
그는 다른 누군가가 그들의 아이들을 가르치고 있다는 사실에 매우 슬퍼했을 것입니다.
I would think "I really want to teach"
'정말 가르치고 싶다'라고 생각해요
"I really want to teach my daughter"
"나는 정말로 내 딸을 가르치고 싶다"
do not worry
걱정 하지마
Let me teach you
내가 가르쳐 줄게
Put your feet on the pedal first and put them up first
페달에 발을 먼저 올려놓고 발을 먼저 올려보세요.
Then step hard and don’t have any worries
그럼 힘내서 걱정하지 말고
Even if you shake and feel like you're going to fall
흔들리고 넘어질 것 같아도
You must never stop and keep moving forward.
절대로 멈추지 말고 앞으로 나아가면 안 됩니다.
What if I do fall?
내가 떨어지면 어떡하지?
No, I'll be right behind you, don't worry
아니요, 바로 뒤에 제가 있을 테니 걱정하지 마세요
let us start
시작하자
Don't let go suddenly, don't let go
갑자기 놓지 마, 놓지 마
Oops, her exercise cells are too bad, right?
앗, 운동세포가 너무 안 좋죠?
This is her first time riding. You should keep supporting her.
이번이 그녀의 첫 라이딩입니다. 계속해서 그녀를 지원해야 합니다.
How can I let go?
어떻게 놓아줄 수 있나요?
To learn well, you have to train rigorously from the beginning
잘 배우려면 처음부터 철저하게 훈련해야 한다
What are you talking about?
무슨 얘기를 하는 건가요?
What to do if you leave a scar
흉터가 남는다면 어떻게 해야 할까요?
I was wrong and sorry
내가 잘못했고 미안해
Hate
싫어하다
- It makes me sad. - I was wrong.
- 슬프네요 - 제가 틀렸어요
- Do you know you are wrong - I was wrong
- 당신이 틀렸다는 걸 알고 있나요 - 내가 틀렸어요
I thought why it was so strange
왜 이렇게 이상할까 싶었는데
It turns out this is time I've never spent before
알고보니 지금은 내가 한 번도 보낸 적이 없는 시간이었어
- Do you know that you are wrong? - I know that you are wrong.
- 당신은 당신이 틀렸다는 것을 알고 있습니까? - 나는 당신이 틀렸다는 것을 알고 있습니다.
in my changed future
달라진 내 미래에
Can record more
더 많이 녹음할 수 있다
Is this kind of memory?
이런 기억이 있는 걸까요?
The little frog is singing
작은 개구리가 노래해요
Children, grandchildren, and daughters-in-law gathered together
아이들과 손자들, 며느리들이 한 자리에 모였습니다.
It would be nice if that was the case
그랬다면 참 좋았을 텐데
It would be great if that was really the case
정말 그랬다면 참 좋았을 텐데
The Yunying one
윤잉이
Do you want to take a bite of the long rice cake?
긴떡 한입 드실래요?
No need for me to do it myself
내가 직접 할 필요는 없어
I'll feed you
내가 먹여줄게
Open your mouth quickly
빨리 입을 벌려
Just accept his apology.
그냥 그의 사과를 받아들이세요.
Just say it doesn't matter. Really?
그냥 상관없다고 말해주세요 정말요?
How delicious is it?
얼마나 맛있나요?
I feed you, so it tastes better, right?
먹여주니까 더 맛있겠죠?
It's inherently delicious
원래 맛있어요
The rice cake is chewy and delicious.
떡이 쫄깃쫄깃하고 맛있네요.
Who is he and why is he at the door of our Teacher Yin’s house?
그 사람은 누구이며 왜 우리 음 선생님 집 문 앞에 있는 걸까요?
probing
프로빙
Didn’t I ask you not to come for a while?
내가 한동안 오지 말라고 하지 않았나요?
Why are you here?
당신은 왜 여기에 있습니까?
I know you are having a hard time now, how could I not come?
지금 당신이 힘든 시간을 보내고 있는 걸 알면서, 내가 어떻게 안 올 수 있겠습니까?
In the past I have also suffered
예전에는 나도 겪었다.
Chairman, you are very helpful.
위원장님, 수고가 많으십니다.
- Please come in. - Thank you very much.
- 들어오세요. - 정말 감사합니다.
Can you let me know before you leave?
떠나기 전에 알려주실 수 있나요?
OK I will
알았어 그럴게
Okay, then I'll wait for your news
알았어, 그럼 네 소식을 기다릴게
Okay, come in quickly
응, 빨리 들어와
Oops
이런
What should I do with that car?
그 차는 어떻게 해야 하나요?
We finally met here
드디어 여기서 만났어요
Who are you
누구세요
so sad
너무 슬퍼
I thought you would recognize me right away
단번에 나를 알아보실 줄 알았는데
Don’t you remember my voice?
내 목소리 기억 안 나?
“This thing starts and ends.”
“이 일은 시작하고 끝나요.”
"Only you can solve it"
"당신만이 해결할 수 있어요"
old bridge telephone
오래된 다리 전화
What did you say?
뭐라고 하셨나요?
Only you can solve this matter from beginning to end
오직 당신만이 이 문제를 처음부터 끝까지 해결할 수 있습니다
I knew you would remember
난 당신이 기억할 줄 알았어
because you are smart
당신은 똑똑하기 때문에
It only takes 5 seconds to solve the twisting dice
뒤틀린 주사위를 푸는데 걸리는 시간은 단 5초
Do you know who I am
내가 누군지 아세요?
How could I not know
내가 어떻게 모를 수 있겠는가?
Where is my father?
우리 아버지는 어디 계시나요?
What did you say
뭐라고 하셨나요
I miss your dad very much
나는 당신의 아버지를 매우 그리워합니다
But are you giving me the time machine I gave you?
그런데 내가 준 타임머신을 나한테 주는 거야?
broken
고장난
Are you happy going fishing with your grandpa?
할아버지와 함께 낚시하러 가는 것이 행복합니까?
Um
음
Come with me next time too
다음번에도 나랑 같이 가자
I also learned to ride a bicycle now
나도 이제 자전거 타는 법을 배웠어요
The scenery we went to today is very good
오늘 갔던 풍경이 너무 좋아요
So I want to go with you again
그래서 너랑 또 가고 싶어
Is that where it won’t be in 2021?
2021년에는 거기가 없을까요?
There should be
있어야 한다
Has the car been repaired?
차는 수리됐나요?
Maybe
아마도
Had known so
그렇게 알고 있었을까
I won’t make an appointment with them to see you tomorrow.
내일 만나기로 약속을 안 할 거예요.
There's no need to go back now
이제 돌아갈 필요는 없어
No
아니요
Anyway, we are the ones who can’t appear here.
어쨌든 우리는 여기에 나타날 수 없는 사람들이다.
No matter what, it has to disappear
무슨 일이 있어도 사라져야 해
And we will meet again soon after we go back
그리고 우리는 돌아가서 곧 다시 만날 거예요
And you
당신은요
Is it really okay to go back like this now?
이제 이대로 돌아가도 정말 괜찮은 걸까?
how could you
어떻게 그럴 수가 있어?
know i'm here
내가 여기 있다는 걸 알아
Sorry to come to you suddenly
갑자기 찾아와서 미안해
I won't tell anyone else you're here
당신이 여기 있다는 걸 다른 누구에게도 말하지 않을 거예요
I will also forget it from now on
나도 이제부터 잊어버릴게
can i sit down
나 앉아도 돼?
Do we really have to send the child away after he is born?
아이가 태어나면 정말 멀리 보내야 할까요?
Send it to Chairman Yoon Byeong-qiu
윤병규 회장에게 보내주세요
right
오른쪽
I already said I would do this
난 이미 이렇게 하겠다고 말했어
Because you think that child is scary and disgusting?
그 아이가 무섭고 역겹다고 생각해서?
right
오른쪽
All right
괜찮은
Then live a good life
그럼 착하게 살아
Don't feel any guilt
어떤 죄책감도 느끼지 마세요
Forget everything and live your life
다 잊어버리고 인생을 살아
Don’t I understand your difficulties very well?
나는 당신의 어려움을 잘 이해하지 못합니까?
It's understandable that you would feel disgusted and frightened.
혐오스럽고 두려운 마음이 드는 것은 당연합니다.
So if you feel very painful
그래서 너무 고통스럽다면
You don’t have to live with your children
자녀와 함께 살 필요는 없습니다.
i can understand
내가 이해할 수
Chairman Yin Bingqiu
인빙추 회장
Very rich and a good man
아주 부자이고 좋은 사람이에요
This is also a good thing for children
이건 아이들에게도 좋은 일이에요
Living in a rich family has everything you need
부유한 집에 사는 것은 필요한 모든 것을 갖추고 있습니다
This is how he will be raised
그 사람은 이렇게 자라게 될 거야
I won’t feel resentment towards my mother.
나는 어머니에 대해 원망을 느끼지 않을 것입니다.
There will be no complaints
불만은 없을 겁니다
He will grow up like this
그 사람은 이렇게 자라겠지
Lie
거짓말하다
How could you not blame me?
어떻게 나를 비난하지 않을 수 있니?
How could you not resent me?
어떻게 나를 원망하지 않을 수 있니?
I abandoned him
나는 그를 버렸습니다
After all, I am a mother who abandoned her children
결국 나는 자식을 버린 엄마다.
Just believe me
그냥 나를 믿으세요
Didn’t you say your name is the same as mine?
당신 이름이 나와 같다고 하지 않았나요?
That kid's thoughts will be similar to mine.
그 아이의 생각도 나와 비슷할 것이다.
real
진짜
will it be so
그럴까?
It was you who brought him into this world
그를 이 세상에 데려온 건 바로 너였어
This alone is a favor enough
이것만으로도 충분한 호의입니다
He would think so
그 사람도 그렇게 생각하겠지
Are you in a good mood?
기분이 좋나요?
Um
음
This time it’s my turn to send away the person who abandoned me
이번엔 내가 버린 사람을 보낼 차례야
I feel inexplicably relaxed
나는 설명할 수 없을 정도로 편안함을 느낀다
Then you can really go back now, right?
그럼 이제 정말 돌아갈 수 있겠죠?
right
오른쪽
But it was really repaired this time, right?
그런데 이번에는 정말 수리가 되었죠?
Should I go back to see the chairman again?
다시 회장님을 만나러 돌아가야 할까요?
Will not
하지 않을 것이다
Because this time a real repairman showed up
이번엔 진짜 수리공이 나타났으니까
Has anyone been here?
여기에 가본 사람 있나요?
The person who called me under the old bridge at that time
그때 낡은 다리 밑에서 나를 부르던 사람
That's the person who built this time machine.
이 타임머신을 만든 사람이 바로 그 사람이에요.
I couldn't believe it at first
처음에는 믿을 수 없었어요
I don't think that person can exist
그런 사람은 존재할 수 없을 것 같아
How can it be
어떻게 그럴 수 있니?
how could i
내가 어떻게 할 수 있니?
How can I have a son?
어떻게 아들을 가질 수 있나요?
You will obviously die in 2022
당신은 2022년에 분명히 죽을 것이다.
Because you're not dead at all
넌 전혀 죽지 않았으니까
Although it is true that he almost died
거의 죽을 뻔한 것은 사실이지만
But he survived in the end
하지만 결국 살아남았지
Because there is a key there that you have overlooked
거기엔 네가 간과한 열쇠가 있으니까
appeared in that hidden future
그 숨겨진 미래에 나타난
it's me
나야
I always wanted to give you another chance
난 항상 너에게 한 번 더 기회를 주고 싶었어
An opportunity to make different choices
다양한 선택을 할 수 있는 기회
And you
당신은요
Sure enough we did it
물론이지 우리는 해냈어
There is a future there that I don’t know about
거기엔 내가 모르는 미래가 있어
These things happened because of that future
이런 일은 그 미래 때문에 일어난 거야
So who is that person?
그럼 그 사람은 누구예요?
secret
비밀
Are you really not going to say it?
정말 말 안 할 거야?
Let's go
갑시다
Just one step away now
이제 한발짝만 더 가면
yes
예
Thanks to some unknown benefactor, I can go back
어떤 알려지지 않은 은인 덕분에 돌아갈 수 있게 됐어
There were still a lot of good times during this period, right?
이 기간 동안에도 좋은 시절이 많았죠?
There must be a lot of grateful moments
감사한 순간이 많을 거에요
It's also because you are here
그것도 네가 여기 있기 때문이야
But after going back
하지만 돌아가고 나면
Will this really change?
이게 정말 바뀔까요?
What should I do if I leave it intact?
그대로 놔두면 어떻게 해야 하나요?
Go back quickly to confirm
빨리 돌아가서 확인하세요
are you ready
준비 되었나요
See you in the future
앞으로 만나요
Well, see you in 34 years
그럼 34년 후에 만나요
- Hello - Has Haejun arrived safely?
- 안녕하세요 - 해준이는 무사히 도착했나요?
I kept you waiting for a long time
너를 오래 기다리게 했어
I arrived grandpa
도착했어요 할아버지
good
좋은
Pick it up quickly
빨리 집어들어
Hello
안녕하세요
Is mom really you?
엄마가 정말 당신인가요?
That's how we are
그게 우리의 모습이야
Back to the future safely
무사히 미래로 돌아가
our present
우리의 현재
Really changed a lot
진짜 많이 변했네
Home
집
changed
변경됨
Yunying
윤잉
This guy
이 남자
Really
정말
where have you been
어디 있었어?
I went to see my mother
나는 어머니를 만나러 갔다.
What
무엇
What is she talking about?
그녀는 무슨 말을하고 있습니까?
Waiting for me to disappear without a trace
흔적도 없이 사라지길 기다리고 있어
Parents who have been waiting for a month
한 달간 기다리신 부모님
Worried me to death
죽을만큼 걱정했어
Became what I had seen in my dreams
꿈에서 본 것이 되었어요
- Smelly girl - don't hit her
- 냄새나는 여자 - 때리지 마세요
For more than thirty years
30년 넘게
He who is always waiting for me
언제나 나를 기다리고 있는 그 사람
Didn't forget our agreement
우리의 약속을 잊지 않았어
Haijun
하이준
but me
하지만 나
Finally met the writer of my dreams
드디어 꿈에 그리던 작가를 만났습니다
became her editor
그녀의 편집자가 되었어요
Mother
어머니
I think this sentence needs to be deleted.
이 문장은 삭제해야 할 것 같아요.
I do not want it
나는 그것을 원하지 않는다
If you want to review the manuscript like this
이렇게 원고를 검토하고 싶다면
Just write your own novel
그냥 당신만의 소설을 써보세요
Acting stubborn again
또 고집 부리는 척
He's becoming more and more stubborn
그 사람 점점 더 고집스러워지네
I mean, go ahead and write your own novel.
내 말은, 가서 당신만의 소설을 써보세요.
Wife
부인
Do you want to give it to her?
그녀에게 주고 싶나요?
for you
당신을 위한
Quite interesting
꽤 흥미로운
Don't make trouble
문제를 일으키지 마세요
besides
게다가
Dad, please be quiet and stop playing.
아빠, 조용히 하고 놀지 마세요.
I loved last Sunday at 9pm
나는 지난 일요일 오후 9시를 좋아했습니다.
Hello everyone, viewers
안녕하세요 시청자 여러분
What you are watching now is "KSBC 9 o'clock news"
지금 보고 계시는 것은 "KSBC 9시 뉴스" 입니다.
Under investigation Songhuan Group Chairman Zhao Mingshi
송환그룹 자오밍스 회장 조사중
Prosecutors suspected of bribery
검찰, 뇌물수수 의혹
Today, for Songhuan Group Corporation
오늘은 송환그룹주식회사를 위해
and 8 related companies to launch seizures
외 8개 관계사 압류 개시
Looks similar
비슷한 것 같아
The biggest doubt is to transfer company funds
가장 큰 의문은 회사 자금을 이체하는 것입니다.
Hee-seop
희섭
elder brother
형
Hello uncle
안녕하세요 삼촌
There are no guests today
오늘은 손님이 없어요
This is a retro bar, so
여기가 레트로 바라서
- Mastered 4 billion won - Dad
- 40억원 마스터 - 아빠
size of funds
자금 규모
Evidence of transfer to the name of Chairman Cho Myung-seok
조명석 회장 명의로의 명의이전 증빙
The details will be reported by reporter Kim Woo-hyun
자세한 내용은 김우현 기자가 보도하겠습니다.
Let's go
갑시다
It feels so strange walking here, right?
여기까지 걸어가니 정말 이상한 기분이 들죠?
Feel better
기분이 나아지 다
Hold hands whenever and wherever you want
언제 어디서든 손을 잡고
Don’t be afraid of speaking
말하는 것을 두려워하지 마세요
By the way, did your parents say anything when they saw me?
그런데 너희 부모님은 나를 보고 뭐라고 하셨나요?
How could I not say it?
내가 어떻게 말하지 않을 수 있겠는가?
Whenever they see the news they say
뉴스를 볼 때마다 그들은 말한다.
You look a lot like their old school teacher
당신은 그 옛날 학교 선생님과 많이 닮았어요
Even the sound is exactly the same
심지어 소리도 똑같음
I feel incredible
정말 믿을 수 없을 것 같아요
Your daughter is also quite suspicious, right?
당신 딸도 꽤 의심스럽죠?
They were indeed suspicious
그들은 정말로 의심스러웠다
Let's get started
시작하자
OMG the long rice cake looks so delicious
아 떡볶이 너무 맛있어보이네요
come to you
너에게로 와
- Oh my god. Please use this.
- 맙소사, 이것을 사용해 보세요.
Eat
먹다
It really tastes the same as what I’ve had before.
예전에 먹었던 맛과 정말 똑같네요.
We were with Yunying at that time
그때 우리는 윤잉이랑 같이 있었어
The same day I was riding a bicycle in the park
그날 나는 공원에서 자전거를 타고 있었다.
It’s been 30 years
30년이 지났어요
There's a friend your mother still misses
엄마가 아직도 그리워하는 친구가 있어요
That's why I named you after her
그래서 내가 그 사람 이름을 따서 네 이름을 지었지
I can't stand it
나는 그것을 참을 수 없다
But you look more and more like her as you get older
하지만 넌 나이가 들수록 점점 그 사람을 닮아가는 것 같아
I never thought something like this would happen
이런 일이 일어날 거라고는 상상도 못했어요
It should have been when you were pregnant with me
당신이 나를 임신했을 때였어야 했어요
I think of that friend often, maybe it’s like that
그 친구가 자주 생각나서 그런가봐요
- Is it is it
- 그거야?
Oops
이런
Do they believe what you say?
그들은 당신의 말을 믿나요?
What if I don’t believe it?
내가 그것을 믿지 않는다면 어떻게 될까요?
Even if we are the same as those 34 years ago
34년 전과 똑같아도
Teacher and friend look exactly the same
선생님과 친구가 똑같이 생겼어요
They never thought it was because of time travel
그들은 그것이 시간 여행 때문이라고는 결코 생각하지 못했습니다
A while ago
얼마 전에
I met that person by chance
그 사람을 우연히 만났어요
You won't do anything to yourself
당신은 스스로 아무것도 할 수 없습니다
Do you regret it?
후회하시나요?
Regret
후회
If you like it, just say you like it.
마음에 들면 그냥 마음에 든다고 말하세요.
If it hurts, just say it hurts
아프면 그냥 아프다고 말하세요
If you're envious, just say envy.
부러워하면 부러워한다고 말하세요.
If only I were more candid too
나도 좀 더 솔직했더라면
Because I couldn't do that
왜냐하면 나는 그것을 할 수 없었기 때문이다.
Because it's too late
너무 늦었으니까
Maybe I will live forever
어쩌면 난 영원히 살지도 몰라
The days of wandering among the crowd
군중 속을 헤매던 날들
It's never too late
너무 늦었 결코
Because now
왜냐면 지금은
To you in the future, it’s the past
미래의 너에겐 과거야
Is that so?
그렇습니까?
Although I don't know how she is doing now
그 사람 지금은 어떻게 지내는지 모르겠지만
but i think maybe
하지만 내 생각엔 아마
she has become more outspoken
그녀는 더 솔직해졌어
but me
하지만 나
Still living on the same side
아직도 같은 편에 살고 있어
While thinking about the future and the past
미래와 과거를 생각하면서
good night, see you tomorrow
잘자 내일 봐
- It's been a lot of fun today - Yeah
- 오늘 정말 즐거웠어요 - 응
I can't look closer
가까이서 볼 수 없어
My mother's face?
우리 엄마 얼굴이요?
Let's talk about it later. If you see it now, you'll be in trouble.
나중에 얘기하자 지금 보면 큰일난다.
Why
왜
It wouldn’t be fun if the ending was spoiled.
결말이 스포라면 재미없겠죠.
For the sake of our future relationship
우리의 미래의 관계를 위해
Sure enough, people who are destined to meet will eventually meet.
물론, 만날 운명이 있는 사람들은 결국 만나게 될 것입니다.
After all, my parents meet again here
결국 우리 부모님은 여기서 다시 만나요
fall in love again
다시 사랑에 빠지게
yes
예
As far as you know, what's her favorite thing?
당신이 아는 한, 그녀가 가장 좋아하는 것은 무엇입니까?
Now that you know everything, give me some tips.
이제 모든 것을 알았으니 몇 가지 팁을 알려주세요.
So that I can prepare the gifts I will give later
나중에 줄 선물을 준비할 수 있도록
It's you
당신이에요
What my mother likes most in the world is you
우리 엄마가 세상에서 제일 좋아하는 건 너야
And the bouquet of flowers you occasionally give her
그리고 가끔 주는 꽃다발도
That really made her happy
그게 그녀를 정말 행복하게 만들었어
- what is this - a gift
- 이게 뭐죠? - 선물이에요
I love so much
나는 너무 사랑한다
I love it
나는 그것을 좋아한다
Are you too easy to dismiss?
당신은 너무 쉽게 해고할 수 있나요?
This little thing makes you so happy
이 작은 일이 당신을 너무 행복하게 만들어요
I already have this gift from you, why should I give it to you again?
나는 이미 당신에게서 이 선물을 받았는데 왜 다시 당신에게 주어야 합니까?
- That's - my gift.
- 그건 - 내 선물이에요.
Is that time machine no longer usable?
그 타임머신은 더 이상 사용할 수 없나요?
I can only run back and forth one more time
한 번만 더 앞뒤로 달릴 수 있어
Anywhere
어딘가에
Did you know that tomorrow is May 16th?
내일이 5월 16일인거 알고 계셨나요?
It seems we think the same thing
우리도 같은 생각인 것 같아
if
만약에
What if I just make this trip?
내가 이번 여행을 떠나면 어떡하지?
how do you feel
기분이 어때?
It should be worth a try this time
이번에 시도해 볼 가치가 있을 것 같아요
Let's go one last time
마지막으로 한번 가보자
I have to try my best this time
이번엔 최선을 다해야지
just in case
혹시라도
What to do if variables occur
변수가 발생하면 어떻게 해야 할까요?
Maybe the "future" will find us
어쩌면 "미래"가 우리를 찾아올지도 몰라
Because we will be together no matter what
무슨 일이 있어도 우린 함께일 테니까
Our meeting was not by chance
우리 만남은 우연이 아니었어
But it is the fate that we must meet
하지만 우리가 만나야 할 운명은
- Are you ready? - Okay
- 준비됐나요? - 알았어
lets go
갑시다